<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environment Management on Zimera Corporation</title>
    <link>/tags/environment-management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environment Management on Zimera Corporation</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:45:51 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/environment-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mamba as Conda Replacement</title>
      <link>/posts/00019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:45:51 +0700</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/00019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;python-and-its-package---environment-management&#34;&gt;Python and Its Package - Environment Management&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://python.org&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; has always been the first choice for many programming tasks. This - of course - debatable since some problems exist in Python world, but let me tell you, in &lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.ieee.org/the-top-programming-languages-2023&#34;&gt;IEEE Spectrum top programming languages&lt;/a&gt;, Python is the winner from &lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Trending&lt;/em&gt; category while SQL beats it in &lt;em&gt;Job&lt;/em&gt; category.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a long time developer who use Python since release 2.x (I insist on using Python for the whole curriculum in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.utdi.ac.id&#34;&gt;Universitas Teknologi Digital Indonesia&lt;/a&gt; back in 2004), currently I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.anaconda.com/free/miniconda/index.html&#34;&gt;Miniconda&lt;/a&gt; a lot (with &lt;code&gt;conda&lt;/code&gt; as its package and environment manager). Conda is a beautiful piece of software of course. I use it to manage my package and create mine. Using it, I can create an environment with specific Python version and also its own packages. However, when I use it for my software with many packages, It runs quite slow. So, I start to look for a drop in replacement. There goes &lt;a href=&#34;https://mamba.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;&gt;Mamba&lt;/a&gt;!. It comes with faster and better at resolving package dependencies. Here&amp;rsquo;s the reason why Mamba is faster and better from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mamba-org/mamba&#34;&gt;Mamba Github&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
