<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data on Zimera Corporation</title>
    <link>/categories/data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data on Zimera Corporation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 22:25:56 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PostGIS - PostgreSQL GIS Extension Installation</title>
      <link>/posts/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 22:25:56 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/14/</guid>
      <description>PostgreSQL - in its default installation - geometric data types for spatial object. More geospatial features exist in PostgreSQL extension - PostGIS. Here&amp;rsquo;s hos to insatll PostGIS extension.
Prerequisites PostGIS needs GEOS and SFCGAL. In Debian-based system, these packages are needed:
gdal-data and libgdal-dev. libgeosVERRSION and libgeos-dev. libsfcgal1 and libsfcgal-dev. protobuf-* and libprotobuf-c-dev dblatex if you want to build PostGIS documentation Build Get the source code, extract:
$ tar -xvf postgis-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tantangan Pengelolaan Data di Era Digital</title>
      <link>/posts/07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 06:48:57 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/07/</guid>
      <description>Organisasi menghadapi tantangan yang semakin kompleks di era digital ini. Era digital merupakan era yang ditandai dengan masifnya penggunaan teknologi berbasis peranti digital elektronik yang memproses angka 0 dan 1 sebagai penanda hidup - mati atau on - off. Peranti digital elektronik sejak dahulu dikenal dengan istilah komputer dan saat ini sudah menunjuk ke berbagai perangkat serta sistem berbasis komputer dalam berbagai skala, mulai dari skala kecil (sub–0.1-mm3) yang bisa diinjeksikan ke dalam tubuh manusia (Shi, 2021) sampai dengan peranti berkapasitas besar yang digunakan dalam suatu data center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using YugabyteDB in Python App Development</title>
      <link>/posts/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 10:16:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/05/</guid>
      <description>As a long time PostgreSQL user, it&amp;rsquo;s normal that YugabyteDB got my attention. It&amp;rsquo;s a distributed SQL database which features-compatible with PostgreSQL so that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to lose my investation. YugabyteDB reuses PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s query layer, so I can use my development tools as usual. It gives me more since there is also Cassandra query layer. Using YugabyteDB I can reuse my SQL skill and development tools, enhanced with NOSQL data model (especially wide-column store), while I have NewSQL&amp;rsquo;s resiliency, scalability, and high performance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
