<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenCypher on Zimera Corporation</title>
    <link>/tags/opencypher/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenCypher on Zimera Corporation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 12:30:22 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/opencypher/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FalkorDB - RedisGraph Fork for OpenCypher-based Property Graph DBMS</title>
      <link>/posts/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 12:30:22 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/18/</guid>
      <description>If you are a software developer, mainly working with data intensive application, chances are, you&amp;rsquo;ve already work with in-memory data as it will make our app runs fast. Redis usually becomes de-facto DBMS for caching. Redis mainly uses key-value data model but its modular architecture makes it possible to develop other tools or data models using Redis key-value as its underlying data model. That&amp;rsquo;s also happens with RedisGraph, a Redis module for property graph model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache AGE - Property Graph - OpenCypher for PostgreSQL</title>
      <link>/posts/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 17:41:41 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/17/</guid>
      <description>Tentang Apache AGE Apache AGE adalah adalah ekstensi dari PostgreSQL untuk model data graph. Apache AGE mendukung model data graph berupa property graph (jenis lainnya adalah RDF/TripleStore). Apache AGE merupakan software bebas dan mendukung berbagai versi PostgreSQL. Secara resmi, pada halaman web Apache AGE, dinyatakan bahwa versi PostgreSQL yang didukung adalah versi 11-15. Meski demikian, pada versi release dari Apache AGE di GitHub, terdapat versi untuk PostgreSQL 16.x. Artikel ini menggunakan versi 16.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
