<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepage on Zimera Corporation</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepage on Zimera Corporation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 05:42:41 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Bambang Purnomosidi D. P.</title>
      <link>/team/bpdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/bpdp/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Bambang Purnomosidi D. P. (also known as bpdp) has a wide range of experiences in software industry and education. He is a Ph.D from DTETI - FT UGM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting Services</title>
      <link>/services/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/consulting/</guid>
      <description>Our consulting services assist businesses or any other organizations with anything related to data and software. We focus on client&amp;rsquo;s critical issues and persistently work to achieve goals. Therefore, it is very important to define the problem since the beginning and stick to it until the solution has been succesfully completed. Specifically, there&amp;rsquo;s Powel&amp;rsquo;s Three C&amp;rsquo;s: Clarity, Consistency, and Commitment as our main concerns in every task/project.
We assist in problem solving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Widyastuti Andriyani</title>
      <link>/team/widya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 05:42:41 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/team/widya/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Widyastuti Andriyani is a Ph.D from DCSE, FMIPA, UGM. Her expertise are in AI and Expert System.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School and Training Services</title>
      <link>/services/school/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:59:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/school/</guid>
      <description>About the School Our school helps in talent or human resources development. Basically, we have some schools which only act as themes grouping. Our schools consist of:
School of Decentralized Systems School of Enterprise Systems School of Software Engineering School of Data Prior to enter Zimera School, a learner needs to understand the basic. It is not that difficult, but one may need to his/her paradigm in learning by consistently challenged his/her ability to solve problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systems Services</title>
      <link>/services/systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:59:06 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/systems/</guid>
      <description>Systems services provide data-related software products. We do not provide services for project-based software systems, instead we engineer some products (in some cases, we also fork some open source software products) and provide services for customization of the software. In case of providing software customization for some open source projects, we will put all of our modification to upstream and so that the software is the same with upstream version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polyglot Programming dan GraalVM</title>
      <link>/posts/06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 10:17:08 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/06/</guid>
      <description>Pernahkah mendengar istilah polyglot programming? Istilah ini sudah menjadi istilah yang umum dan barangkali banyak didengar oleh para developer yang sehari-hari memang berkutat dengan bahasa pemrograman dan peranti pengembangan. Polyglot programming merupakan penggunaan lebih dari satu bahasa pemrograman untuk menyelesaikan suatu masalah pemrograman. Kategori polyglot programming antara lain adalah:
Penggunaan binding yang dibuat menggunakan suatu bahasa pemrograman tertentu (biasanya bahasa pemrograman aras sistem — atau aras rendah seperti C/C++, Assembly, Rust) ke suatu bahasa yang berada pada aras tinggi seperti Ruby, Python, dan lain-lain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using YugabyteDB in Python App Development</title>
      <link>/posts/05/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 10:16:30 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/05/</guid>
      <description>As a long time PostgreSQL user, it&amp;rsquo;s normal that YugabyteDB got my attention. It&amp;rsquo;s a distributed SQL database which features-compatible with PostgreSQL so that I don&amp;rsquo;t need to lose my investation. YugabyteDB reuses PostgreSQL&amp;rsquo;s query layer, so I can use my development tools as usual. It gives me more since there is also Cassandra query layer. Using YugabyteDB I can reuse my SQL skill and development tools, enhanced with NOSQL data model (especially wide-column store), while I have NewSQL&amp;rsquo;s resiliency, scalability, and high performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Idiomatic Programming</title>
      <link>/posts/04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 10:15:26 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/04/</guid>
      <description>Salah satu hal yang menghambat orang untuk belajar adalah banyaknya istilah-istilah yang membingungkan. Semua domain pengetahuan biasanya memang mempunyai istilah-istilah sendiri dan meskipun ada satu istilah yang muncul di lebih dari satu domain pengetahuan, pengertiannya seringkali tidak sama sehingga pemahaman tentang istilah bersifat context-dependent (harus dilihat konteksnya).
Mempelajari pemrograman juga kurang lebih harus memahami berbagai macam istilah yang muncul. Kali ini saya akan menjelaskan sedikit tentang istilah idiomatic programming. Jika anda sering membaca mailing list, newsgroup, atau berbagai macam resources di Internet, terutama yang terkait dengan pemrograman, barangkali akan sering mendengar istilah-istilah berikut:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing a Software Development Team: Some Experiences</title>
      <link>/posts/03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2023 10:14:33 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/03/</guid>
      <description>Managing a software development team is never an easy task. It consists of 2 sides:
technical things non-technical things. This task is often assigned to the project manager, VP Engineering, Software Development Manager, etc. To be succeed, one has to consider those 2 sides. In this article, I will ouline some of my experiences in managing a software development team. This list is not meant to be complete nor perfect. You may need more but at least you will be in the safety line level one if you do care with these issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Development: Welcome Changing Requirements?</title>
      <link>/posts/02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 10:13:33 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/02/</guid>
      <description>If you ever being in a team which practices agile software development, you might already heard about how a software development team &amp;ldquo;welcome chnging requirements&amp;rdquo;. While it sounds great, I personally think, if this statement is not properly explained, the impact will be negative on the development team side. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s see the complete statement:
Welcome changing requirements, even late in development. Agile processes harness change for the customer’s competitive advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Values for Software Developer</title>
      <link>/posts/01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 10:11:27 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/01/</guid>
      <description>So you are interested in software development and want to become one who do that job. Initially you think that it’s only a matter of coding. creating source code, have them compiled, and then deploy the software for the customer/client. Later on, you realize that developing software is hard. Even harder since so many things beyond technical issues are also involved. Suddenly you realize that what you have learned in school is not enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Zimera Corporation was founded on February 14th, 2022 under the name of PT Zenit Merdeka Raya. The name Zimera has a simple meaning, taking from African language: one that creates. This name becomes the underlying philosophy of Zimera Operation: to create. In a broader sense, we do really appreciate anybody who creates something. It is not limited to just create a software per se, but also other things: create a better SOP (Standard Operating Procedure), create a solution to a problem not related with software creation, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description> Day Opening Hours Monday - Friday 9:00am - 16:00pm Saturday - Sunday Closed </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
